SOURAV DUTTA

https://sourav-oss.github.io Medinipur, West Bengal, 721516 sodutta1234@gmail.com | 7602672314



About Me -

I am a front-end developer with hands-on skills and experiences in a wide range of software, tools and programming languages. I have been working with web development since 2019 and for the last few years I have been working nearly with React and Node.js and focusing on backend development and rest APIs using Express.js and MongoDb.

Objective -

Secure a responsible career opportunity to fully utilize my training and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the organization.

I am willing to relocate anywhere. I am fond of learning new tools and technologies.

Work Experience -

A) Software Engineer (Front-end Development)

June 2022 - Present

Indus Net Technologies, Kolkata, India

> Software Engineer (Front-end Development)

June 2022

B) Senior Front-end Developer (Team Leader)

April 2019 – May 2022

Webhibe Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Kolkata, India

- > Team Leader (Front-end Development)
 December 2021
- > Senior Front-end Developer March 2020
- > Web Designer
 April 2019

Skills & Technologies -

My expertises are HTML, CSS, Bootstrap & CSS libraries, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React-Redux, REST APIs, PHP, Photoshop, Figma, Git version control, Progressive Web Application and Responsive Website Design.

Personal Skills -

- Base Strong understanding and experience on programming, web concepts and frontend technologies. Design, code, test, review, build and release.
- Open Always up for new ideas and able to take and give feedback in a positive way.
- Driven sets high goals, doesn't give up, and motivated to ensure that their job gets done on time and meets/exceeds expectations.
- Curious Aware of new technologies and uses them to make new improvements in the Engineering ecosystem.

- Smart Innovative and thinks out of the box, in difficult situations finds a way to succeed no matter what
- Responsible takes ownership of tasks given and has a strong work ethic.
- Advantage: Knowledge on backend technologies like Node.js, Express.js, Cloud/AWS.

Education -

Bachelor's Degree - Computer Application

Jul 2016 - Aug 2019

Vinayaka Mission Sikkim University, Kolkata, India

Higher Secondary (10+2) - Science

Jun 2014 - May 2016

West Bengal Council of Higher Secondary Education (WBCHSE)

Certificate in Computer Application

October 2014

Sahaj Tathya Mitra Kendra (Govt. of WB) - SA/WB/CCA/424/Oct14

Contact Details -

Website: https://sourav-oss.github.io/

Email: sodutta1234@gmail.com

Call: 7602672314

Location: Malida, Pirakata, Paschim Medinipur, West Bengal, 721516, India

[✓] I hereby declare that all statements made in this resume are true, complete and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.